(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-25T08:58:58.185212",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
苦手だとか恐いとか気づかなければ
If I hadn't noticed what I was bad at or scared of,
俺だってボールと友達になれた
I too could've been friends with the ball.
頭が悪いとか思わなければ
If I hadn't thought I wasn't smart,
きっとフェルマーの定理すら解けた
I'm sure I could've even solved Fermat's Last Theorem.
すれ違ったマサヤに笑われなければ
If Masaya hadn't laughed as we passed each other,
ずっとコマ付きのチャリをこいでた
I'd have kept riding my bike with training wheels forever.
力が弱いとか冴えないとか知らなかったら
If I didn't know I lacked strength or coolness,
俺が地球を守ってた
I would've been the one protecting Earth.
破り捨てたあの落書きや
The scribbled drawings I ripped up and threw away,
似合わないと言われた髪型
The hairstyle people told me didn't suit me,
うろ覚えの下手くそな歌が
The clumsy, half-remembered songs I sang—
世界を変えたかも…
Maybe they could've changed the world...
かつて天才だった俺たちへ
To us who were once geniuses,
神童だった貴方へ
To you who were once prodigies,
似たような形に整えられて見る影も無い
Trimmed into a similar shape, leaving no trace behind.
いまだかつてないほど入り組んだway
A way more intricate than ever before,
悩めるだけ悩み
Worry as much as you want,
時が来たらかませ
And when the time comes, let loose!
風まかせ どっちみちいばらのway
Leave it to the wind, it's a thorny path anyway.
俺らは大器晩成
We are late bloomers.
時が来たらかませ
When the time comes, let loose!
i wanna be a 勝者
I wanna be a winner,
i wanna be a 強者
I wanna be a champion.
まだ見ぬ高みへ駆け込み乗車
Rushing aboard toward heights yet unseen,
花火のような運命だろうが
Even if it's a destiny like fireworks,
我が身果てるまでやりきれそうや yay
We'll see it through until our bodies give out, yeah!
生まれてこの方一体いくつ
Ever since I was born, just how many
分岐点を見過ごしてきたんだろうか
forking roads have I let pass by?
墓場に入るまであと一体いくつ
Until I reach the grave, just how many
可能性の芽を摘んでしまうのだろうか
potential buds will I end up plucking?
稀代のうつけ者 or 天下人
A peerless fool or a ruler of the realm,
orいまだかつて醜いアヒルの子
Or still an ugly duckling,
ほらどうぞご指導ご鞭撻の程
Go ahead, guide and whip me into shape.
渡る世間の洗礼を浴びるとこ
Receiving the baptism of the harsh world,
俺はキャンパスかなり薄汚れた
My canvas became quite grubby,
だけどワンチャンスまだ余白はあるさ
Yet there's still a chance, there's blank space left.
ちゃっかり目立ったり劣ったり
Casually standing out or falling behind,
この隔たりよ永遠に
May this gap remain forever.
かつて天才だった俺たちへ
To us who were once geniuses,
神童だった貴方へ
To you who were once prodigies,
何にだってなれたanother way
You could've been anything, another way.
まだ諦めじゃない
It's not over yet,
いまだかつてないほど入り組んだway
A way more intricate than ever before,
悩めるだけ悩み
Worry as much as you want,
時が来たらかませ
And when the time comes, let loose!
風まかせ どっちみちいばらのway
Leave it to the wind, it's a thorny path anyway.
俺らは大器晩成
We are late bloomers.
時が来たらかませ
When the time comes, let loose!
i wanna be a 勝者
I wanna be a winner,
i wanna be a 強者
I wanna be a champion.
まだ見ぬ高みへ駆け込み乗車
Rushing aboard toward heights yet unseen,
花火のような運命だろうが
Even if it's a destiny like fireworks,
我が身果てるまでやりきれそうや yay
We'll see it through until our bodies give out, yeah!
お前は未だに広がり続ける銀河
You are still a galaxy continuing to expand,
孫の代までずっとフレッシュマン
Freshmen all the way down to your grandchildren.
荒探しが得意なお国柄
In a country where finding faults is a specialty,
シカトでかまそうぜ金環日食
Brush it off and rock on through the annular eclipse.
俺も未だに広がり続ける銀河
I am also still a galaxy continuing to expand,
今際の間までずっとフレッシュマン
Freshmen right up to my final moments.
くたばり損ねて冥土からcome back
Failing to kick the bucket, coming back from Hades,
草葉の陰からゴングフィンガー
A gong finger from the shade of the grass.
無傷のままで居られない変わり続けてく多面体
Can't stay unscathed, a multifaceted being continuously changing.
その物差しじゃ測れない測らせる気も無い
Can't be measured by that ruler, nor do I care to let you.
かつて天才だった俺たちへ
To us who were once geniuses,
神童だった貴方へ
To you who were once prodigies,
まだ見ぬ明日へ羽ばたき行けぜ12345
Spread your wings and fly toward a tomorrow yet unseen, 12345.
いまだかつてないほど入り組んだway
A way more intricate than ever before,
悩めるだけ悩み
Worry as much as you want,
時が来たらかませ
And when the time comes, let loose!
風まかせ どっちみちいばらのway
Leave it to the wind, it's a thorny path anyway.
俺らは大器晩成
We are late bloomers.
時が来たらかませ
When the time comes, let loose!
あい
Hey.
てことで、みなさん、こんばんはー！
So everyone, good evening!
ホロライブ3期生の団長の白銀ノエルだー！
Hololive 3rd Gen leader, Shirogane Noel!
すまいる、すまいる、すまいる、ということで、えっと、
Smile, smile, smile, so, um,
団長、今回、リリカルLIVE開催です！いえーい！
Danchou, this time, Lyrical LIVE is being held! Yay!
えっとな、最初の曲はですね、まあ、かつて天才だった俺たちへ、ということで、
Um, the first song is, well, "To Us Who Were Once Geniuses,"
団長の好きな、あのクリーピーナッツさんの曲です。
Danchou's favorite song by Creepy Nuts.
まあ、この曲、あの、
Well, this song, um...
団長、ダンスとかがんばってって言ってたのに、あれ？ダンスしてないじゃんって思ったそこの君！
You out there thinking, "Wait, Danchou, you said you'd work hard on dancing, but aren't you not dancing?!"
ええと、ダンスは次の曲からいきます！
Um, dancing starts from the next song!
ちょっとね、リリック乗って、ちょっとイマジナリーなね、団長も
Riding the lyrics a bit, feeling a bit imaginary, Danchou also...
ちょっと映った気がした気がするんですけど、
felt like she appeared a bit, but...
まあね、ちょっと団長、ちょっとダンスのね、そう、ダンスしない香りにちょっと、うー、イマジナリーということでね、はい、ちょっと分身をだしました。
well, you know, Danchou... kind of having an aura of not dancing, ooh, imaginarily, yeah, I brought out a clone.
次は歌って踊って、アイドルとかするのかな？どうなんでしょうか！
Next is singing and dancing, will she do idol stuff? I wonder!
さて、じゃあ、ちょっと場所を移動して、リリカルLIVEスタートしましょう！もしよければハッシュタグでたくさんスクショとか、えっと、ツイートしてくださーい！
Now then, let's move locations and start Lyrical LIVE! If you like, please take lots of screenshots with the hashtag and tweet them!
ではでは、リリカルLIVEスタートー！
Well then, Lyrical LIVE start!
裏路地の真ん中で慣れない景色と
In the middle of a back alley, with unfamiliar scenery
嗅がない匂いに私は覆われて染まっていくんでしょう
and unfamiliar scents, I'm getting covered and dyed in them.
私は怖がりで知らないことには手を付けず
I'm a coward, never touching things I don't know,
誰かがやってきてロクミをするまで待っていた
waiting for someone to come along and vet things for me.
することは単純でマニュアル通りの生活を来る日も淡々と過ごしていた
What I do is simple, living a routine life day in and day out just like the manual.
そういやそういやそういや
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
昨日の私もこうだった
yesterday me was just like this too.
そういやそういやそういや
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
弱い音を吐いている 薄っぺらい人間です
I'm just a shallow human venting weak complaints.
一歩前に出るのはやめときます 絡まれたくはないからさ
I'll refrain from stepping forward, 'cause I don't want any trouble.
描いた理想像に 現実味がないからさ
Since the ideal image I drew lacks any realism,
近づけないよう生きときます 明日も同じよう過ごします
I'll live keeping my distance, spending tomorrow just the same.
路地裏の真ん中でいつもの夕日を薄目で眺めて胸の内で呟いていた「いつまで続くんだろう」
In the middle of the back alley, squinting at the usual sunset, I muttered in my chest, "How long will this last?"
そういやそういやそういや
Yeah, yeah, yeah,
昨日の夕飯これだった
yesterday's dinner was this too.
そういやそういやそういや
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
臆病で切りが悪い 意気地無し人間です
I'm a cowardly, indecisive, spineless human.
一歩後ろに下がって逃げときます 目立ちたくなかんないからさ
I'll step back and run away, 'cause I don't want to stand out at all.
描いた理想像に 現実味がないからさ
Since the ideal image I drew lacks any realism,
近づけないよう生きときます 明日も同じよう過ごします
I'll live keeping my distance, spending tomorrow just the same.
弱い音を吐いている 薄っぺらい人間です
I'm just a shallow human venting weak complaints.
一歩前に出るのはやめときます 絡まれたくはないからさ
I'll refrain from stepping forward, 'cause I don't want any trouble.
ため息ばっかでさ 吸う息足りないの
Just sighs and not enough breath to inhale...
そう上手くはいかないけどさ 試しにちゃんと生きてみよう
It won't go so well, but let's try living properly for once.
だいたい それで いいんじゃないの
Isn't it fine if it's just about good enough?
適当だって いいんじゃないの
Isn't it fine if it's a bit sloppy?
少し不安を残した方が 楽しく生きられるんじゃないの
Isn't it better to leave some worry so you can live happily?
疲れたら寝ればいいんじゃないの
Isn't it fine to just sleep when you're tired?
たまには楽していいんじゃないの
Isn't it fine to take it easy once in a while?
やりたいことやるために 僕らは生きているんでしょう
We're living to do what we want to do, aren't we?
だいたい それで いいんじゃないの
Isn't it fine if it's just about good enough?
失敗しても いいんじゃないの
Isn't it fine even if you fail?
どんなに悩んだってほら 結局タイミングなんじゃないの
However much you worry, look, isn't it all about timing in the end?
一つ一つ抱え込んで 一体何をどうしたいの
Clutching this and that one by one, what on earth do you want to do?
やりたいことやるために 君は生まれてきたんでしょう
You were born to do what you want to do, weren't you?
完璧な生き方なんてできないから
Because I can't live a perfect life,
完璧な生き方なんてしたくないから
because I don't want to live a perfect life,
不器用な 僕は 不器用な ままで
I'll stay as clumsy as I am.
かみさま この歌が聞こえるかい
God, can you hear this song?
あなたが望んでいなくても
Even if it's not what you hoped for,
僕は笑っていたいんです
I want to laugh happily,
泣きたいときは泣きたいんです
I want to cry when I want to,
いつだって正直でいたいんです
I always want to be honest with myself.
誰もが二度と戻れぬ 今を
Since everyone will surely regret
きっといつか後悔するから
the irreplaceable present someday,
今はまだ こんな気持ちで 気ままに歩いていたっていいよね
it's alright to walk as I please with these feelings for now, right?
だいたい それで いいんじゃないの
Isn't it fine if it's just about good enough?
無理はしなくていいんじゃないの
Isn't it fine not to overdo it?
つくりわらいしたってほら ちっとも楽しくないでしょ
Even if you put on a fake smile, look, it's not fun at all, is it?
一つ一つ抱え込んで 一体何をどうしたいの
Clutching this and that one by one, what on earth do you want to do?
誰も百点満点の答えなんて出せないでしょ
Nobody can come up with a 100% perfect answer, can they?
完璧な生き方なんてできないから
Because I can't live a perfect life,
完璧な生き方なんてしたくないから
because I don't want to live a perfect life,
不完全な 僕は 不完全な ままで
I'll stay as imperfect as I am.
かみさま この歌が聞こえるかい
God, can you hear this song?
あなたが望んでいなくても
Even if it's not what you hoped for,
僕は笑っていたいんです
I want to laugh happily,
そして今叫びたいんです
and right now I want to shout it out.
いつだって最後はNo Logic
Always, in the end, it's No Logic.
僕らのこの一度きりの夢 どうせいつか終わりが来るなら
This once-in-a-lifetime dream of ours—if an end is bound to come someday,
生きることをやめたいときだけ
then only when I want to stop living,
立ち止まって考えるくらいで いいよね
it's fine to stop and think about it for a bit, right?
やりたいことだけ選んでいらないもの君捨てて 誰もがみんなそんなふうに歩けるわけないよね
Choosing only what you want and discarding what you don't need—it's impossible for everyone to just walk through life like that, right?
はい お疲れ様です
Thank you for your hard work!
「No Logic」でした
That was "No Logic."
その1曲前は「弱虫モンブラン」聞いていただきました
Just before that, you listened to "Yowamushi Mont Blanc."
いや けっこうね 男女「弱虫モンブラン」わー！って感じんでね けっこう歌ってるから
I sing both versions quite a bit, feeling all hyped up!
ちょっとこの曲 あ、ライブバージョン お! こんな感じか!って思ってくれたリスナーいると思うけど
I think some listeners might be thinking, "Oh, so this is what the live version of this song is like!"
「No Logic」はね 多分初めて歌ったと思うんですけど
But I think this was probably my first time singing "No Logic."
ちょっとすごいね めちゃめちゃ団長好きな曲で
It's an amazing song, one of my absolute favorites,
なんか 「人生って」っていう感じがして
and it gives off this real "life goes on" kind of vibe.
いや正直ね ライブのもっと後ろに持てくれば よかったかなー
Honestly, I kinda wish I could've put it a bit later in the setlist!
ちょっと序盤で ちょっと人生語っちゃったなーと思いつつ ま ここからね ちょっと あれです 通常衣装とは おさらばし
Thinking, "Ah, I started talking about life a bit early," but from here on, saying goodbye to my normal outfit...
ちょっとね 結構 歌ったり踊ったりな アイドルっぽくね なってこうかなーと思いますので
we'll become a bit more idol-like, singing and dancing, so please keep tuning in!
RTしてツイートしてくれると嬉しいです！
I'd be so happy if you retweeted!
では、参ります！
Now then, let's go!
眠るサカナ
Nemuru Sakana (Sleeping Fish)
夜が来た 眠れずに今日も
The night has come, and once again today I cannot sleep.
雨降り、振り、振られて、
Rain falls, falling, shaking off...
待ちぼうけ、一人のベッドに沈むサカナ
Waiting in vain on my bed alone, a sleeping fish.
今夜窓から抜けだしたのは
Tonight, what slipped out of the window
白い渡り鳥
was a white migratory bird.
夜風に揺れる羽根にくるまって
Wrapped in feathers fluttering in the night wind,
目を閉じた
I closed my eyes.
眠れない夜はこうやって君を思い出してみる
Restless nights are always like this, trying to recall you.
会えない日もそうやって隠してきた
Days we couldn't meet were hidden away just like that.
どう？
How is it?
傘を開いて窓を叩くよ
Open your umbrella and tap on the window,
裸足のまま連れ出すんだ
I'll drag you out while barefoot.
部屋の明かりを消したら
When the room's light is turned off,
手を伸ばして、さあ！
Reach out your hand, come on!
踊り出すミュージック！
The music starts dancing!
夜が来た 一人きり今日も
The night has come, and once again today I cannot sleep,
雨降り濡れたままでって
staying soaking wet in the falling rain.
君の手を思い出しながら 眠るサカナ
While thinking of your hand, a sleeping fish.
眠れない夜はこうやって君を思い浮かべてみる
Restless nights are always like this, trying to picture you in my mind.
会えない日もそうやって隠してきた
Days we couldn't meet were hidden away just like that.
どう？
How is it?
窓をたたく雨にまぎれたら
Once I'm caught in the rain tapping on the window,
裸足のまま泳いでゆくよ
I'll swim away barefoot.
部屋の明かりを消したら
When the room's light is turned off,
手を伸ばして！
Reach out your hand!
眠れない夜はこうやって君を思い出してみる
Restless nights are always like this, trying to recall you.
会えない日もそうやって隠してきた
Days we couldn't meet were hidden away just like that.
どう？
How is it?
傘を開いて窓を叩くよ
Open your umbrella and tap on the window,
裸足のまま連れ出すんだ
I'll drag you out while barefoot.
部屋の明かりを消したら
When the room's light is turned off,
手を伸ばして、さあ！
Reach out your hand, come on!
踊り出すミュージック！
The music starts dancing!
ガラス窓の 向こう側に
Beyond the glass window,
十字架と 海がみえる
a cross and the sea can be seen.
君は 仕事仲間たちに
You are surrounded by your coworkers
シャンパンを つがれている
as champagne is poured for you.
君のパパに 泣かれた時
When your father was moved to tears,
胸の奥で 誓ったよ
I swore deep within my heart
この愛を この愛を
This love, this love—
大切に 守り抜くと
I swore to protect it dearly.
思い出が 輝いて ここにある限り
As long as our memories shine here,
いつまでも 変わらない あの頃のまま
staying unchanged just like those days forever,
お願いジュピター お願いジュピター
I pray to Jupiter, I pray to Jupiter—
あの時の君 透明な夏
you of that transparent summer.
空に投げた あのブーケで
With that bouquet tossed into the sky,
幸せに なれた人は
those who found happiness...
運命を 運命を
Destiny, destiny—
本当に 信じてたから
because they truly believed in it.
思い出が 輝いて ここにある限り
As long as our memories shine here,
いつまでも 変わらない あの頃のまま
staying unchanged just like those days forever,
お願いジュピター お願いジュピター
I pray to Jupiter, I pray to Jupiter—
あの時の君 永遠の夏
you of that eternal summer.
Kissして どんなときも
Kiss me no matter what,
笑顔で 照らしていて
and light up my life with your smile.
好きだから こそする喧嘩
Fights born from deep affection...
それも大切
are precious too.
思い出に 火をともし 語り明かそうよ
Let's light a fire in our memories and talk all night.
小さな子供達を 膝に座らせ
Sitting little children on our knees,
お願いジュピター お願いジュピター
I pray to Jupiter, I pray to Jupiter—
あの時の君 透明な夏
you of that transparent summer.
あの時の君 永遠の愛
you of that eternal love.
お願いジュピター
I pray to Jupiter...
ちょっとやそっとじゃ止まらない キミのマシンガントーク
Won't stop for anything at all, your endless machine-gun talk
時々迷惑に感じるくらい please please don't disturb me
To the point where it sometimes feels annoying, please, please, don't disturb me
ソンジョソコラの男たちには手にも負えないレベルのyou're my honey
You're my honey, on a level ordinary guys can't even handle at all
ボクには分かってるんだよ それがキミの愛のカタチ
I understand it completely, that's your form of love
どんなに小さな出来事だって please please tell me all about you
No matter how small the event, please, please, tell me all about you
世界中の誰よりもずっとキミのこと知っていたいから
Because I want to know about you longer and better than anyone else in the world
シャワーのように降りかかるコトバの雨に打たれていたいい
I want to be beaten by the rain of words falling like a shower
good time bad time
いろいろあるけれど it's all right
there's all sorts of things, but it's all right.
キスして抱きしめてる時だけはホントに静かだね
Only when we're kissing and holding each other are you truly quiet.
i want you want これ以上スキになるとヤバイ
I want you, want you—it'd be dangerous to like you any more than this.
離れられない
I can't break away.
ランチの合間も止まらない キミのマシンガントーク
Even during lunch break, your endless machine-gun talk won't stop.
冷めたコーヒーで渇きを潤し please please tell me o- about you
Quenching my thirst with cold coffee, please, please tell me all about you.
まるでコンタクトレンズのようにキミとずっと一緒にいるから
Because I'm always together with you like contact lenses,
疲れた心を癒すコトバの海に溺れていたいい
I want to drown in the sea of words that heal a tired heart.
good time bad time
いろいろあるけれど it's ok
there's all sorts of things, but it's ok.
ケンカや誤解や仲直りホントに忙しいね
Fights, misunderstandings, and making up—you're really busy.
i want you want 大切なトキを2人で過ごそう
I want you, want you—let's spend precious moments together.
離れたくない
I don't want to part.
見えるものだけ信じちゃダメだよ
You mustn't believe only what you can see.
見えないモノを見なきゃダメだよ
You have to look at what you can't see.
聞こえることだけ信じるよりも聞こえないことを聞いてかなきゃ
Rather than believing only what you hear, you have to listen to what you can't hear.
コトバの裏側に隠されてる真実がちゃんと見えてるかい?
Can you clearly see the truth hidden behind the words?
そういうことを忘れずにいれば oh yeah
If you keep things like that in mind, oh yeah...
good time bad time
いろいろあるけれど it's all right
there's all sorts of things, but it's all right.
キスして抱きしめてる時だけはホントに静かだね
Only when we're kissing and holding each other are you truly quiet.
i want you want これ以上スキになるとヤバイ
I want you, want you—it'd be dangerous to like you any more than this.
離れられない
I can't break away.
good time bad time
いろいろあるけれど it's ok
there's all sorts of things, but it's ok.
ケンカや誤解や仲直りホントに忙しいね
Fights, misunderstandings, and making up—you're really busy.
i want you want 大切なトキを2人で過ごそう
I want you, want you—let's spend precious moments together.
離れたくない
I don't want to part.
あい！
Yay!
わためえ…
Watame...
今日は来ていただきありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming today!
こちらこそありがとうございます！
Thank you so much as well!
今日はね、うん、はい。
Today, um, yeah.
なんで呼ばれちゃったの？うん。
Why did you invite me? Yeah.
あの団長ね、あのずっとずっと、そのわためとね、あの歌って踊りたかった曲があって。
Um, Danchou, you see, um, there was a song that I've wanted to sing and dance with Watame for a long time.
おっ？
Oh?
いや、わため、ま、さっきね、ま、歌ったから、ちょっと分かると思うんだけど、ま、ちょっとそれ、忘れちゃって。
Well, Watame, since we sang it just now, you probably know, but... wait, I completely forgot that part!
え、わためって好きなアーティストさん、誰かな？
Um, who is your favorite artist, Watame?
ええと、ポルノグラフィティです！
Um, Porno Graffitti!
そうだよね、ライブも見てたもんね。で…
That's right, you've been watching their live shows too. And...
団長も実はポルノグラフィティ好きなんだよ！
Actually, Danchou loves Porno Graffitti too!
なにー！？
What?!
なんだってー！？
You're kidding?!
な、ま…
Th-, well...
してると思うけど、それで一番好きな曲が
I'm sure you know, but my absolute favorite song...
あのマシンガン・トークで
is, you know, Machine Gun Talk.
そう、だからね、ずっとずっと二人でね、歌ってみたいなと思っていました。
That's right! So I've always wanted us to sing it together.
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
いや本当にかっこいい、こんなコアなねポルノの曲が歌えると思いませんよね。
Truly, I never thought we'd get to sing such a hardcore Porno song.
そう、すごいもう20年以上前の曲？
Yeah, it's an amazing song from over 20 years ago! 20 years...
ちょうどね、そんな中黒猫のね、アルバムの、そうかアルバムの曲、そう曲でね、やってくれてありがとうございます。
Right, and a track from Porno's Kuroneko album... Thanks for featuring it.
こちらこそ、今日こそはね。
The pleasure is mine, and today...
うん、そう、あの、団長ちょっとわためとに、あとね、やりたいことがあって
Yeah, so today, Dancho, Watame and I... actually there's something I want to do.
え、何？
Eh, what?
うん、うん、あるんだけど... ちょっと
Yeah, yeah, there is... but wait...
え、でさ、なんか... だから団長ちょっとね、チューしないでしょ？
Eh, wait, but... so Dancho, you're not going to kiss me?
違うの？ 違うの？
Huh? No, no!
そんなことないよ。違うよ。
That's not what I meant! No, no.
え、でもさ、こんなほら、ふたりこのね、おそろっちのTシャツ着たし、ちょっとね
And look, we're wearing matching T-shirts like this, so...
ね？ いや、このTシャツね、でっかいよね。
Right? Man, these T-shirts are huge.
近くにね、離れたくない。
Let's get close, I don't want to be apart.
近くに行ってさ、で、でっかいね。
Let's get close... And they're huge!
え、ちょっと...
Eh, wait...
そういうのはなしで、そういうのなしで。
no way, none of that.
え、なし？
Huh? None of that?
はい、なし。
Yeah, none of that.
え、でもなんか、なんか、なんか綿あじ出てる？ なんかじーっと見てるね、なんか吸い込まれちゃ
Eh, but like, is some cotton candy coming out? You're staring so hard, like you're getting sucked in...
ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ、なんか... あ、ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ、ちょっ、なんか、これはいけませんね。
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait... ah, wait, wait, wait, wait, this is no good!
ぎりわた、だれ！？
Who on earth is Giriwata!?
dance beat 乗っかって
Riding on the dance beat,
心通じ合っていく
our hearts connect.
さらけ出して
Bare it all
頂戴 感情を 手を鳴らして clap your hands
and show your emotions, clap your hands!
back beat 乗っかって
Riding on the backbeat,
夜な夜な踊っていこう
let's dance the night away.
今宵 ノラリクラリ 自由 本能 存在 証明 が したい
Tonight, carefree and free, I want to prove my existence.
ならば 踊らにゃ損 踊らにゃ損です
If you don't dance, you're missing out!
君と舞いたい 舞いたいだけです
I just want to dance and be with you.
ならば 踊らにゃ損 踊らにゃ損です
If you don't dance, you're missing out!
心踊れない毎日なんて 私気に食わないわ
Days where my heart doesn't dance just don't sit right with me!
ミラーボール輝いて 心照らし合っていく
The mirror ball shines, illuminating our hearts.
暴き出して頂戴 表情を 引かれ合ってテイクオフはハイ
Bare your expressions, drawing each other in, take off high!
洒落たビート溶かして
Dissolving the stylish beat,
舞い踊って最前線
dancing at the forefront.
今宵洗いざらい話してくれ 傍観者じゃもったいない
Tonight, tell me everything; it's a waste to just watch!
故に 踊らにゃ損 踊らにゃ損です
Therefore, if you don't dance, you're missing out!
君と舞いたい 舞いたいだけです
I just want to dance and be with you.
ならば 踊らにゃ損 踊らにゃ損です
If you don't dance, you're missing out!
心踊れない毎日なんて たまにゃあってもいいわ
It's okay to have days where my heart doesn't dance sometimes!
されど惹かれる方へ 誰も知らない方へ
Yet towards where we're drawn, to the unknown,
どこまでも行けそうな そんな日々を過ごして
spending days where we feel we could go anywhere.
夜が明けては また繰り返す このままずっと 胸が騒ぐ方へ
Night breaks and repeats, towards where my heart beats with excitement.
ならば 踊らにゃ損 踊らにゃ損です
If you don't dance, you're missing out!
君と舞いたい 舞いたいだけです
I just want to dance and be with you.
ならば 踊らにゃ損 踊らにゃ損です
If you don't dance, you're missing out!
心踊れない毎日なんて 私気に食わないわ
Days where my heart doesn't dance just don't sit right with me!
朽ち果てた心に i need you
In a decaying heart, I need you
噂のアルカロイド
The rumored alkaloid
あだ名はネットのしゃれこうべ かき鳴らせディストーション
Nickname is the net's skull, strum distortion
付け焼き刃の侍が
The amateur samurai
乱れ打ち散弾銃
Firing scattered shotguns
悲劇の歴史で踊ろうか
Shall we dance in the history of tragedy?
ほら テンテコ ヘンテコ舞い
Look, tenteko, henteko dance
僕の心はエゴロック
My heart is Ego Rock
斜め45度 ナンセンス
45 degrees tilted nonsense
ノウハウ砕いてマンネリを
Crushing know-how and monotony
明日にバイバイバイ
Say bye-bye-bye to tomorrow
媚びへらうその姿 吐き気の空模様
The fawning posture, a nauseating sky
シニカルな視線の雨 今日も両目を塞ぐふり
Rain of cynical gazes, today too pretending to close both eyes
おちゃらけ頭に i need you
In a playful head, I need you
ちまたのアルカロイド
The town's alkaloid
あの子も流行りのインスタントショー 巻き散らせPID
That child is already an instant show, scatter PID
頷かぬ侍が
The samurai who won't nod
未踏の哀悼歌
The uncharted elegy
無惨な歴史で歌おうよ
Let's sing in a tragic history
ほら ちゃんちゃら なんちゃら舞い
Look, chanchara, nanchara dance
ロックな心で生きようか
Shall we live with a rock heart?
真夏日和 ホットなミュージック
Midsummer weather, hot music
ハウトゥー砕いて丸描いて
Crushing how-to, drawing circles
明日もわははは
Tomorrow too, wahahaha
しゃらくささも癖になる はみ出し者だろ
Even audacity becomes a habit, you're a misfit
シニカルな視線の雨 今日も両目を開くふり
Rain of cynical gazes, today too pretending to open both eyes
透明な感情は染まるだけさ
Transparent emotions just get dyed
だったら見て見ぬふりする奴らを押し出せ
Then push away those who pretend not to see
人生かけても負けそうですか
Are you about to lose even with your life on the line?
勝ち負け取り憑かれナンセンス
Possessed by winning and losing, nonsense
1分砕いて常識を
Crush normality for a minute
未来にセイグッドバイ
Say goodbye to the future
僕の心はエゴロック
My heart is Ego Rock
斜め45度 ナンセンス
45 degrees tilted nonsense
ノウハウ砕いてマンネリを
Crushing know-how and monotony
明日にバイバイバイ
Say bye-bye-bye to tomorrow
媚びへらうその姿 吐き気の空模様
The fawning posture, a nauseating sky
シニカルな視線の雨 今日も両目を塞ぐふり
Rain of cynical gazes, today too pretending to close both eyes
1 2 3 ファックユー
1 2 3 Fuck you
はーい
Hii!
みんな、これ、ジャンプ見えとる、見えとる？
Everyone, can you see this jump?
みんなのすげえ驚いてる顔が見えとるよ！
Everyone's super surprised faces can be seen!
ああ、ジャンプです！おーい！
Ah, it's a jump! Oii!
てことで、ちょっと、ジャンプなんか変わったところ気づきましたか？
So, did anyone notice something different with the jump?
ま、気づいてない人はいないと思います。
Well, I don't think there's anyone who hasn't noticed.
ジャンプ、なんと、なんと今回ね、あの、
Jump, amazingly, this time, um,
前々から運営さんにお願いしていた
from before requested from management,
100万人記念の新衣装が出来上がりました！
the new outfit for 1 million subscribers is finished!
イエーイ！いや、今回はね、なんと、そのお披露目も
Yay! No, this time, um, incorporating that reveal as well,
兼ねたライブになっていまして。いや、びっくりしたっしょ？
it became a live. Man, you were surprised, right?
いやね、めちゃめちゃ、動きやすくなったんですよ。
Man, it became so much easier to move.
いや、これ早くホロメンにも見てほしいな。
Man, I want the other Holomembers to see this soon.
お姉ちゃんかわいいね！
Big sis is cute!
え、なんか、これ、おっさん？あれ、なんか、
Eh, wait, is this an old man? Huh, wait,
前フリが、前フリがあったな、いま。え、男のおっさんかと思ったけど、
there was a setup just now. I thought it was an old guy, but
この声は、えーと、じゃあちょっと、
this voice is, um, then a bit,
ヤカマシの「ヤ」からよろしくお願いします。
from the "Ya" of Yakamashi, please.
元々だよ！
It was originally like that!
ヤカマシの「ヤ」誰や！ヤカマシの「ヤ」誰やねん！
Who's the "Ya" of Yakamashi! Who the heck is it!
あれ、コロねじゃないの？あ、ヤカマシの「ヤ」
Huh, isn't that Korone? Ah, the "Ya" of Yakamashi...
はあ！
Haa!
コロねです！あ、コロねーん！わあー！
It's Korone! Ah, Korone-n! Woo!
こま誰や！ラミィじゃない！
Who is Coma?! That's Lamy!
ラミィです！ラミィ！わかりやすいね、マオマオラミィ！
It's Lamy! Lamy! Easy to understand, Mao Mao Lamy!
艶かしのC白銀ノエル、イエーイ！
The lustrous C, Shirogane Noel, yay!
いや～こうしてね、作ってもらったんでね。
Ah, since they made this for me...
ちょっとちょっと下からさ、もっとアップで舐め回すように...
From a bit lower down, let's get a close-up...
ちょっと、ちょっと研究してこいしょ、下から...
Wait, let's do some research, from below...
足元から、足元からチェック。
Let's check from the feet.
あ、この靴に騎士のマークが... あ、そうなのよ！
Ah, this boot has the knight's emblem... Ah, that's right!
はい！付いてますね。かわいい、かわいい。
Yes! It's there. So cute, so cute.
よいしょ、よいしょ。あ、なんか舐め回すとか恥ずかしいな。
Heave-ho... Ah, saying "inspect closely" is so embarrassing.
まだいく？もっと？え、もっと食い込んでいる？
Still going? More? Eh, is it digging in more?
そう、ベルト付いてる。よく見たらも付いてます。
Yeah, there's a belt. Look closely, it's there too.
あら、いやらしい。これ、紐外し... 外したらどうなっちゃうの？
Oh, how lewd. This string... what happens if you untie it?
いや、外したらもう... 外したら外せないよ、バカ！外せないよ、バカ！
No, if you untie it... you can't untie it, you idiot! You can't untie it!
紐ほどいて遊んじゃおうかな。え、キモ！
Shall I untie the strings and play with them? Eh, gross!
お、後ろ！あ、可愛い！
Oh, the back! Ah, cute!
いいじゃん、いいじゃん。めちゃ可愛いよ。いいですね。
Nice, nice. Super cute. This is nice.
お尻の、なんか携帯ホルダーみたいな付いてるじゃん。
On the hip, there's like a phone holder attached, right?
これ、これ、このメースがね、いつも...ちょっと、ちょっと長靴ね、踊ってたから...
This mace... since I was dancing earlier, the mace wasn't there...
あ、なるほどね。おっ、背中可愛くない？
Ah, I see. Oh, isn't the back cute?
背中、ほら！見える？見える？背中！
Look at the back! Can you see? Can you see? The back!
可愛い！さあ！まあね、いつもね、背中見えてるけど。
Cute! Now! Well, my back is always visible, though.
なんぞこれ？真ん中ちゅるちゅる？
What is this? A little hole right in the middle?
真ん中ちゅるちゅる？謎仕様だぞ？お風呂上がり？
A little hole in the middle? What a mysterious design. Just out of the bath?
もう何回も見せちゃった。あとメース好きだよん。
I've shown it so many times. And I love the mace.
おっと。忘れちゃいけない。メースないと落ち着かないからね、騎士として。
Oops. Can't forget that. I can't settle down without my mace, as a knight.
よし、どう？今。すごい可愛い。
Alright, how is it now? Super cute.
胸元すごくない？胸元すごくない？もっとアップで。
Isn't the chest area amazing? More close-up!
お、いいよ、いいよ、いいよ。おじさんじゃん、あーら。
Oh, nice, nice, nice. You look like an old uncle, oh my.
なんかアップにされるのがさらにちょっと、なんかあれだね、刺激的やね。
Having it zoomed in more makes it even a bit... stimulating.
収まらない、収まらないよ！脱げないのですか？
It won't fit, it won't fit! Can't you take it off?
え、これ、これ黒いのを脱げ...。あ、お！
Eh, can you take off the black part... Ah, oh!
めっちゃ脱げるんだけど、ちょっとYouTubeくんがね、ちょっと、ちょっと、ちょっと、ちょっと離れてカメラ。
It comes off so easily, but YouTube-kun might... a bit further away from the camera.
なんか手で隠して、手で隠しながら...。あ、そうそうそうそうそう。
Cover it with your hand, while hiding it... Ah, yes, exactly.
これもな、ちょっと、ちょっと、外れた？外れた？
This too, a bit... did it come off? Did it come off?
まだ、あ、あ、あ！見せて見せて！あはははは！
Not yet, ah, ah, ah! Show me, show me! Hahaha!
まあね、こんくらい、ちらリズムよ。
Well, about this much, just a peek.
いいじゃん。めちゃ可愛い。
That's nice. Super cute.
髪型がさ、白銀ノエル、の色がなんかね、違うよね。
The hairstyle... Shirogane Noel's color is a bit different, right?
ちょ、髪の毛の毛先が... グラデ、グラデよ！
Wait, the tips of the hair... gradation, gradation!
グラデ、おしゃれになってて、ピンも都会に染まっちゃって。
Gradation, looking stylish, even the pin got dyed by the city.
ええ、グラデグラデよ。
Yeah, gradation gradation.
今めちゃくちゃしたかったんだよ。あらよ。
I really wanted to do this right now. Here you go.
いいね、そのヘアピン欲しいわ、マジで。グッズで欲しいです。
Nice, I really want that hairpin. I want it as merch.
欲しいです。あ、そのことはちょっと覚えといて。
I want it. Ah, keep that in mind.
グッズで欲しい。分かった。ゲットしとったからね。
I want it as merch. Understood. I got it.
後ろから... エイはね。
From behind... A is...
後ろに見せてよ。あ、ポニーテール、いいよ！
Show me from behind. Ah, ponytail, nice!
大きく動いたよ。独特なんだよな、この動き。
It moved a lot. This movement is so unique.
ちょっと待って、動きがね、振り返って、振り返って。
Wait, the movement... turn around, turn around.
あ、可愛い！脇じゃん。
Ah, cute! Armpits.
わーい！脇じゃん。
Yay! Armpits.
そういえば、そういえば何だって？
Come to think of it, what did you say?
あれなの、そう！みんなさ、天の声だと思って油断しとるっしょ？
That's right, yeah! Everyone thinks it's the voice of heaven and gets careless, right?
はいはい、違う。いるがの、みんないるよ。ちょっと待っててね。
Yes, yes, that's wrong. They're here, everyone is here. Wait a second.
いるの？いるじゃん。
Are they here? They're right here.
え、いるよ。
Eh, they're here.
いないよから。え、いる！みんなさ、みんな、みんな足りないよ。だって。
"Not here" my foot. Eh, they're here! Everyone's missing something. That's what you said.
いらないだろ、逆にそんなの。いらないだろ、何でだよ。
You wouldn't need that kind of stuff anyway. Why would you?
大変だよこれ。みんな、なんでもできる。
This is tough. Everyone can do anything.
おしゃマリンでしょ。全然似てないよ。
It's stylish Marine. Not looking like her at all.
あ、見てほら、艶かしい！嬉しいな。
Ah, look, lustrous! I'm happy.
何でマリン被ってきてお前！被ってくんなら...
Why are you wearing Marine's outfit! If you're gonna wear it...
いや、このポーズちょっとやりたい。真似するの？
Man, I want to do this pose. You're going to copy it?
え、じゃあ、艶かしの矢から順番に... 矢から行こっか。
Eh, then, starting from lustrous Ya... Let's start with Ya.
よし。よろしくね。艶かしのこ、あ、こ、こうか？
Alright. Nice to meet you. Lustrous Ko... Ah, Ko, like this?
足が違う、足が。足、足をね、広げて広げて。広げて！
The legs are wrong, the legs. Spread your legs, spread them. Spread them!
あ、可愛い！いいね、ポーズ！
Ah, cute! Nice pose!
いいね！なんかファンのオタクみたいになってるな。こうじ、こいつと同じポーズ取ってみたみたいな。
Nice! It looks like a fan or an otaku. Like trying to do the same pose as this guy.
で、えっと、や、かだね、か。かお、波の... 脇ドル感？
And, um, Ya, Ka, right? Ka. Ka-O, wave... armpit idol vibe?
脇ドル感ある、あい、とる？
Has an armpit idol vibe, I-idol?
あ、可愛い！片足大変だな。
Ah, cute! One-legged is tough.
え、いいよ、どういう感じ？こんな感じ。
Eh, nice, what kind of feeling? Like this.
できてるよ。ちょっとこれ、絶妙なポーズ取れるかな？
You're doing it. Can you strike this exquisite pose?
傾きが大事。
The tilt is important.
違う、違う、星が！
No, no, the stars!
あははははは！
Ahahaha!
なんじゃこりゃ
What is this?
もうじょうじょうやんこんな
This is getting out of hand!
え、これリンボーダンスかな？
Eh, is this limbo dance?
リンボーダンス、スピッツ
Limbo dance, Spitz...
いやちょっとリンボーダンスいいな、ころねのリンボーダンス
No, wait, limbo dance is nice, Korone's limbo dance.
すごいね、なんでもできるじゃん
That's amazing, you can do anything!
ありがたみが増したんだ
The gratitude has increased!
今日ね、やっぱね動きやすい衣装ね、お願いしてて
Today, we asked for easy-to-move-in outfits,
そうだから今日はまだまだ踊りたいと思います
so that's why today we want to dance even more!
嘘嘘嘘、いや結構動ける
No way, well, we can move quite a bit.
せっかく動きやすい衣装になったからなんかポーズとってもらうかな
Since our outfits are easy to move in, strike a pose!
私ね、やからシークレットスリースラロットポーズもやりますか
Me? Should we also do the Secret Three-Slot pose?
や、シークレットスリースラロットね
Yeah, Secret Three-Slot, right.
ああやりましょう
Ah, let's do it.
じゃあちょっと待ってね。で、みんなが見えてほしいからこう
Then wait a minute. So everyone can see you, like this...
ああ、なるほど
Ah, I see.
あ、ひとりよ助かる。じゃあ、か、えっと、ま
Ah, that helps. Then, um, well...
あ、そういう感じ？はい、レシ
Ah, like that? Yes, rece—
じゃあ、お願いしまーす。じゃ、頭スロットは、じゃあ、ラミーいこかな
Then, please. For the head slot, Lamy, let's go with you.
頭ラミーで行こか
Head Lamy, let's go with that.
で、から上半身は？上半身じゃ、あ、てか、ここね
And upper body? Upper body, then, ah, wait, here...
じゃ、下半身は、バニーにしよう。じゃあコロネ、下半身で。
Then lower body, Bunny. Korone, lower body.
で、なんすか、顔は、やっぱ顔型を見せたいから
And the face? I want to show the face shape,
ちょっと横向いてもらって、あ、そっちだね、そっちだね。
so turn sideways, ah, that way, that way.
で、の、ウインクとかにしようかな。
And then from around there, let's do a wink.
あ、なるほど、ウインク。で、ちょっと首かしげてほしいな。
Ah, I see, a wink. And please tilt your neck.
あー、なるほど。いいね、いいね、いいよ。なるほどね。オッケー。
Ah, I see. Good, good, good. Okay.
すごいいいびしてる。
She's really deliberating over it.
じゃあね、じゃあ上半身はね、そうだな、ちょっと、か、鏡気味にして
Then, upper body, leaning forward a bit...
で、ちょっと、お胸が重そうで大変だから、手で持ち上げて
And since my breasts look heavy, lift them up with your hands!
はい、いいよいいよいいよいいよ。はい、じゃあ、バニー
Yes, good, good. Yes, then, bunny...
で、下半身は？バニーとね、じゃあ
And for the lower body? Bunny, and then...
できる限り開いてもらって、怪しくなってきたね。
Open them as wide as you can... It's starting to look suspicious.
あ、結構開く。で、ちょっと内股みたいな。どういうこと？
Ah, it opens quite a bit. And, like pigeon-toed?
難しいな。なんだこのポーズ。プルプルするぞ。
That's difficult. What kind of pose is this? I'm shivering.
あ、膝つけてもらおうかなそしたら。あ、膝つきね。
Ah, maybe I should have you kneel then. Ah, kneeling.
とんでもないよこのポーズ
This pose is outrageous!
ウインク？ウインク？
Wink? Wink?
ひとりだけおかしいってポーズ。全然ウインクできてない。
Only me looking weird in this pose. I can't wink at all.
でもこれね、正解スロットだよこれ。本当？やっかましい
But this is the correct slot. Really? Shut up!
じゃあちょっと見てみるか。ひとりだけ座ってるよ。
Then let's check. Only one person is sitting down.
ねえ、嬉しい。このポーズ大事にしてくわ。
Hey, I'm happy. I'll treasure this pose.
ありがとう！じゃ、このあともいっぱいちょっと歌って踊るから
Thank you! Well, after this we'll sing and dance a lot,
三人にはこの特等席でな、見ててくだせえよ。
so you three, from this special seat, watch over us!
あ、全然見てますよ。
Sure, we're watching.
ありがとう！応援してね。がんばってね。
Thank you! Cheer for me. Do your best.
バイバリーン！バイバイ！バイバイ！
Bye-bye-reen! Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
シリウス
Sirius
誰かが勝手に決めたレディメイドな今を脱ぎ捨てて
Stripping off the ready-made today that someone else decided,
裸足で走っていく
I'll run away barefoot.
間違ったって転んだって擦り剥いた痛みも
Even if I take a wrong turn, stumble, and scrape myself,
自分仕様な明日になる
the pain will become my very own customized tomorrow.
突き上げたこの手に握り締めた
In this hand I thrust upward, I tightly grasped
誓いが光になっていつか君に届くその瞬間まで
the vow that will turn into light, until the moment it reaches you someday.
泣いてる暇なんてないから
I don't have time to be crying,
突き上げた
Thrust upward
この手に
in this hand,
握り締めた
tightly grasped
誓いが光になって
the vow turning into light...
The oath becomes light,
いつか 君に届く その瞬間まで
Until that moment when it reaches you someday,
泣いてる 暇なんて ないから
There's no time to be crying,
はみ出してしまった 熱い想いが
The passionate feelings that overflowed
夜空で 輝きだす
Start shining in the night sky.
生まれてきた意味が わかった気がした
I felt like I understood why I was born.
願い事は 全部 この手で 叶える
I'll make every single wish come true with these hands.
不安に抗うだけでも 精一杯で
Even just fighting against anxiety takes everything I have,
終わってしまっていた 昨日があったけど
Even though yesterday ended up feeling like that,
立ち止まってた そんな時間も
Those moments when I stopped in my tracks
必要だったのかななんて 今は思うよ
I wonder now if they were necessary after all.
暗闇を切り裂き 辿り着いた 景色のその向こうに
Beyond the scenery I reached by slashing through the darkness,
いつも君がちゃんと 待っててくれてた
You were always waiting for me right there.
愛おしく 煌めく 世界で
In this lovely, sparkling world,
流星群 追い越し 高く高く 心が叫ぶ先へ
Overtaking meteor showers, higher and higher, toward where my heart cries out,
もらっている以上に あげられるように
So that I can give back even more than I've received,
ねぇ 未来は 全部 この手で 叶える
Hey, I'll make the future come true with these hands.
膝を抱えていた夜も 涙で迎えた朝も
Even the nights I hugged my knees, even the mornings I met with tears,
どんな時も まばゆい星みたいに
Like dazzling stars at any given time,
突き上げたこの手に 握りしめた
Clenched in this hand I thrust upward,
誓いが光になって
The oath turns into light,
いつか君に届くその瞬間まで
Until that moment when it reaches you someday,
泣いてる暇なんてないから
There's no time to be crying,
はみ出してしまった 熱い想いが
The passionate feelings that overflowed
夜空で 輝きだす
Start shining in the night sky.
生まれてきた意味が わかった気がした
I felt like I understood why I was born.
願い事は 全部 この手で 叶える
I'll make every single wish come true with these hands.
そう 未来は 全部 この手で 叶える
Yes, I'll make the future come true with these hands.
はい！愛どるにしたかった団長のシリウスでした！
Yes! That was "Sirius" by Dancho, who wanted to make it an idol song!
いや、これね、ちょっと匂わせてたの気づいたかな？
Man, did you guys notice I was dropping hints about this?
団長最近の歌ってみたとかでちょっと練習してたので、
I've been practicing it recently in my cover songs and stuff,
いやもしかしたらライブこれ歌うじゃないかって思ってた人もいると思うんですけど、その人は正解です！
so I'm sure some of you thought, "Hey, maybe she'll sing this at the live?" If you thought that, you're spot on!
という感じで、いや本当にあのライブもだんだんとう終盤に、
And so, honestly, as the live is reaching its climax—
終盤どころかもうあと一曲、いやまだまだ、ちょっとここでは、えもう一曲ならちょっといいかと思ってブラウザバックしようとしたそこのできみ、
or rather, not just the climax, there's only one song left... no, wait, there's still more! To anyone who thought "Guess that's it" and tried to hit back on their browser right here,
なんと重大告知が、ずずずずず、ずん！2つあります！
surprise! There are two major announcements!
白銀ノエル 3D新衣装記念2022グッズが発売されます！どんどんぱふぱふ！
Shirogane Noel's 3D New Outfit Commemoration 2022 goods are going on sale! Yay, fanfare!
という感じでね、まぁ詳細の方ちょっと話していくとですね、
So yeah, getting into the details a bit...
あの今回、まぁこうやって新衣装になりました！
this time, as you can see, I got a new outfit!
まあやっぱ衣装でね、アクリルスタンド欲しいんじゃないかなと思ったので、
Well, since I thought you might want an acrylic stand in this outfit,
団長この新衣装記念して、アクリルスタンドを作ってみました。
I made an acrylic stand to commemorate this new outfit!
まあ、団長がね、これあれです、撮ったんですよ、本当に。団長が撮りました。
Well, Danchou took the photos for it herself, really. Danchou took them.
まあ、団長がね、これあれです、撮ったんですよ、本当に。団長が撮りました。でいう感じでぜひぜひ通常で常設で白銀ノエル通常のアクリルスタンドも絶賛販売中なのでもしよければふたつ並べて飾ってください！
So please check it out! Also, Shirogane Noel's regular acrylic stands are currently on sale, so if you'd like, please buy two and display them side by side!
他はね、星願い先生描き下ろしのランダムキーホルダーちょっと団長ね、こうよちゃんとかがランダムキーホルダーしてるのを見ていいなと思ったので、団長もね、すごいリリカルな動きをしたこのキーホルダーもぜひぜひゲットしてみてください！
Next is the random keychain illustrated by Hoshinegai-sensei! Seeing Koyo-chan and others with random keychains made me want one too, so please be sure to get this keychain with Danchou's very lyrical movements!
で、あとはこれが一番目立つかもしれないんですけど、団長のこのここら辺の紋章をあしらったネクタイピンを用いいたしました。なので、白銀聖騎士団のネクタイピンこちらもぜひつけて、今後ちょっとお出かけしていただけると嬉しいと思います。
And then, this might be the most eye-catching item: a necktie pin adorned with Danchou's emblem right here. So please wear the Silver Knight Order necktie pin when you go out in the future!
カバンには星願いちゃんのランダムキーホルダー団長のペッてつけてまずフルセットで買っていただけるとなんと団長のチェキ風ブロマイドカードもついてくるので複製サイン入りなのでぜひそちらもゲットしてください！
Attach Danchou's random keychain to your bag, and if you buy the full set, you'll also get a Cheki-style bromide card with Danchou's replicated signature, so please get that too!
という感じで、これが重大告知1なんですけど、重大告知2はこれからお披露目していきたいと思います。今日のライブ、なんとリリカルライブだったんですけど、そのもとになったものです。
With that, that was the first major announcement, but for the second major announcement, I'd like to unveil it now. Today's live is called Lyrical Live, and this is what it's based on.
ではではお披露目したいと思いますので、ぜひぜひ最後まで聞いてってね！えい！えい！
So without further ado, let's unveil it, please listen all the way to the end! Yay! Yay!
Ring-Dong Ring-Dong 心音がBeat it 期待もHeat up 感じて
Ring-dong, ring-dong, my heartbeat beats it, expectations heat up
リリカルMonster
Lyrical Monster
ジャジャ！もっとエンジョイ！リリカルSexy！
Ta-da! More enjoy! Lyrical sexy!
上々気分 もっとつよつよHomeRun
High spirits, even stronger home run!
団長無心の才能 ヒェラルKeyword 見せてあげる
Danchou's innocent talent, showing you the hiedral keyword!
Lovely Party ぴるるーんぴるるーん 巻き起こるぜ Typhoon
Lovely Party, piruruun piruruun, a typhoon is brewing!
もっとHappy とことんとことん届けちゃうよ そうだろう こんなろう トキメキたろう La La Love it いかがですか？
More happy, delivering it all the way! Right? Like this, pounding with excitement, La La Love it, how do you like it?
ちょっとVivid感じたら 止めらんないとめどないくらい
If you feel a little vivid, you can't stop it, endlessly!
胸のドキドキ 同期 一瞬待って 現在進行ぐるぐる 追いかけっこ アラララ a la mode このまいくよ
The pounding in my chest syncs up, wait a second, currently ongoing, spinning around, playing tag, Ararara a la mode, going just like this!
Ring-Dong Ring-Dong 心音がBeat it 期待もHeat up もっと感じて
Ring-dong, ring-dong, my heartbeat beats it, expectations heat up, feeling it more
ジャンプにジャンピング ディスプレイをJamming
Jumping, jumping, jamming the display!
おさんぽ気分 新世代ナイト 異論反論は認めません
Stroll mood, next-generation knight, no objections or counterarguments allowed!
史上最高のコトバマイスター U&I ここからReady
The greatest wordmeister in history, U&I ready from here!
ずっと見てて デジタルのモンスターギラ
Keep watching me, digital monster Gira!
リリカルMonster
Lyrical Monster
まっすぐかます 猪牙Boom Boom もっと騒げ Put your hands up Boom Boom
Straight on, boar's tusk boom boom, make more noise, put your hands up boom boom!
Talkだけじゃない ノートの基本 ほめてのびて 烏長って
Not just talk, the basics of notes, praising and growing, like a crow's leader!
あびぴゃーん テンパるの無いTyphoon やっぱCrazy ビシバシビスト飛ばしちゃうよ
Aby-pyan, a typhoon without panicking, so crazy, letting out sharp-sharp beats!
キミはLaugh キミはLaugh るんるんラツガル O Ka Wa Ri いかがですか？
You are laugh, you are laugh, run-run ratsugar, O Ka Wa Ri, how do you like it?
もっとビビッと感じてよ やめらんない目が離せない
Feel it more vividly, can't stop, can't take my eyes off!
キミの＃ハッシュタグHack もう一回回って通常運転のびのびいつも通り アラララ a la carte そのままいくよ
Your #hashtag Hack, spin around once more, normal operation, stretching freely as always, Ararara a la carte, going just like this!
Ring-Dong Ring-Dong 予想は不穏 想像以上のShow time するから
Ring-dong, ring-dong, predictions are uneasy, making a show time beyond imagination!
バンピバンピ 騎士団パニック 拍子ない 発言も寛容
Bumpy bumpy, knighthood panic, out of sync, even remarks are generous!
朗読なんかじゃありません 空前絶後のコトバマインジャン
It's nothing like reading aloud, an unprecedented and peerless word magician!
Yes or Yes なんでもAlright 一緒にSinging リリカルマスマジック
Yes or Yes, anything is alright, singing together, lyrical magic!
団長のライブ 今日は来てくれて
Thank you for coming to Danchou's live today!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
なんでリリカルライブって言ってたかわかったしょ？
Now you know why I called it a "Lyrical Live," right?
最後まで盛り上がっていってねー！
Keep getting hyped all the way to the end!
一味違う時もあるよ
Sometimes it's a bit different,
そこがイイトコロ
and that's the best part.
どんな日も笑顔にするからさ
Because I'll make any day a smiling one.
どんどん笑って相乗効果
Laughing more and more creates synergy!
ニコニコ100満点 アラララLove & Peace
Smiling at 100 points, oh-la-la, Love & Peace!
このまま行くよ まだまだ行くよ
We'll keep going just like this, keeping going further,
ついてきてよね
so make sure to follow me!
Ring-Dong Ring-Don みんななら
Ring-Dong, Ring-Don, if it's all of you,
Ring-Dong Ring-Don 出来るはずさ
Ring-Dong, Ring-Don, you can definitely do it!
Ring-Dong Ring-Don 聞かせて
Ring-Dong, Ring-Don, let me hear it!
Ring-Dong Dong 大きな声で
Ring-Dong, Dong, with a loud voice!
Ring-Dong Ring-Don 鼓動がBeat it
Ring-Dong, Ring-Don, your heartbeat is beating,
気持ちもHeat it もっと感じて
your feelings are heating up, feel it even more!
Jumping Jumping ディスプレイをJamming
Jumping, jumping, jamming the display!
ゆるふわ太郎 ハピネス太郎
Yuru-fuwa Taro, Happiness Taro!
異議反論は認めません
No objections or counterarguments are allowed,
史上最高の団長だから
because I'm the greatest leader in history!
ますますLoving？
Loving it more and more?
一緒にSinging Star!
Singing together, Star!
Amazing!
Lyrical Monster!
はーい！
Hi there!
シショーと新曲お披露目ライブどうでしたでしょうか？
How did you like the Shishow and new song reveal live?
楽しんでもらえたなら団長嬉しいです。
If you enjoyed it, Danchou is so happy.
そしてね、ここでちょっとだけおしらせがあります。なんとなんとこのライブ中に！
And you know, I have a little announcement here. Believe it or not, right during this live,
ホロライブ公式スタンプ「白銀ノエル」が発売されましたー！
the Hololive official stamp "Shirogane Noel" went on sale!
もう現在ね、もうLINE多分買えると思うので、こちらもぜひぜひ買ってください！いっぱいねLINEしてください。
You can probably buy it on LINE right now, so please definitely get it! Send lots of LINE messages.
まあLINEする友達がいない人は団長とね妄想上に友達になりましょう。
Well, if you don't have friends to LINE with, let's become imaginary friends with Danchou in our heads!
そして、あの後日このライブの感想会をするんですが、その時に、あの団員さんのね、あのビジュアルを発表しようと思います。お待たせして申し訳ございません！
And, we'll be having a reflection party for this live at a later date, and at that time, I'm planning to reveal the Danchou-san visuals. I'm so sorry for keeping you waiting!
いや、ぜひぜひあの感想会も、うん来て下さると嬉しいです。
Yeah, I'd really love it if you could come to the reflection party too.
ではでは、他のねいっぱいたくさんころめんが素敵な配信をしてると思うので、団長はおいとまします！
Well then, since everyone else is probably streaming wonderful things, Danchou will be taking her leave!
皆さん、これからもよろしくね！大好きだぞ、んーーーまっ！
Everyone, thank you for your continued support! I love you so much, mwah!